Translator:  lakeisle
Proofreader: O-Ren
Timing created by O-Ren
I can't call it 'memory' yet.
It's still going on.
I would feel like this until all the members die.
I think the story of Hide and X
will continue as a 'progressive form'.
The guidepost which goes forward remains the same as the first.
Let me talk about next year's schedule.
I'll show you a little "Rocket Dive" which I'm still working on.
Here you are.
This song is going to be released next year.
I just finished a meeting with the staff about what to do next year.
I can't tell you anymore, but I think I'll be busy next year.
I have full schedules from January to December.
Next year, I'll release a single that I'm making now.
As I said in the magazine interview, I formed another new band based in LA.
I'll also release the band's album and perform live concerts.
And after the third solo album with this song "Rocket Dive" comes out next spring, it will be early summer.
What will be the schedule from early summer to the end of the year?
I'm going on a six-month tour.
So make money by working part-time.
On December 10, 2014, the album "Co Gal" released in 16 years.
Hide is still running.
Where does such a fascinating charm come from?
He's the one who changed my life.
A lot of things have changed since I met him.
The meeting itself seems to be destiny.
What did he mean to me?
Hide's 50th anniversary.
Hide's colleagues gathered for his birthday event.
Kawasaki, CLUB CITTA
[♪ Ever Free]
Let me free, let me out.
Let me, let me free. Let me out.
I asked someone, "I lost heart to fall in love".
Then the answer with a sigh came back.
"How much does it cost to buy love?"
I asked the kid, "I've lost the season of dreaming".
And then you laughed and said. "Is a dream something to eat?"
Looking at the falling sun...♪
At the same time, it was broadcast in Haneda and Osaka.
[♪ Ever Free] The first melody which is disappearing.
Where did I get lost?
Your dreams, which others call shit, are shaking in my heart.
I think he is the one who pioneered the way.
Hide is someone who discovered our music.
He completely changed my life.
[♪ Ever Free] Ever Free, Where to Free ♪
He taught me that there is more than one solution.
He had a strong sense of justice.
He was responsible for his role, and made a good environment for the people around him.
He was like a carnivore on stage.
I thought, "That is Hide".
I thought, "Another monster came into X".
He kept changing but he did not change.
He was incredibly deliberate.
No matter how much time passes, the mystery will not be solved.
No one can solve the mystery of Hide.
He has known it himself.
I told him, "Why should I play your songs again?"
I played the guitar with anger.
[♪Ever Free] The first memory which is disappearing.
Where is this headed?
Your freedom, which others call shit, is still sleeping with having the wings folded.
Ever free, get out of this night.
Can I fly freely when I open my eyes?
Ever free, where to? free, ever free ♪
When he came up with a new idea, he developed it like painting over the idea.
Who else can do that?
[♪Ever Free] Fu Fu ever free in your sight. ♪
Yokosuka, Dobuita Street
There was a place called Dobuita Street where many US soldiers came.
I went there almost everyday.
I learned all about alcohol, tobacco, and women over there.
Back in the day, all the stores on the street were playing rock music.
I got interested and went into the store like this.
Even though I was scared, I kept going there.
And then, I made friends in there and formed a band.
Hide's first band "Saver Tiger".
He played the guitar in the band and entered the musician's path.
On December 13, 1964, hide was born.
The Home town is Yokosuka, the real name is Hideto Matsumoto.
Hide's brother and the personal manager Hiroshi Matsumoto.
He is currently the representative of "Headwax Organization", which is founded by Hide.
My three year older brother hide, to him, his stuff was his stuff, and my stuff was also his stuff.
Even if we buy the same things, he said, "Your thing doesn’t matter if it is broken, but my thing is very precious".
He painted his own plastic models beautifully.
And he assembled mine in an instant, and threw it away.
I hated him.
He was a bad guy.
His drawing skill was not the level of elementary school students.
When he wrote, the sentences were amazing.
One day, he did my homework instead.
And I was called to the teacher and asked, "Matsumoto, what books are you currently reading?"
In my childhood before I aimed for rock music, I was a fat boy.
I don't remember what my fat percentage was.
It was when I was in elementary school.
I came back from lunch and they let me run because I was fat.
Hide said, "When I was called to the playground, there were only fat students there".
"They let us run".
He kept telling me that he felt very humiliated at that time.
The boy, Hide, became interested in guitars.
My brother played the folk guitar at that time.
"do, re, mi, fa, so, la, ti, do". I also learned the basic scale.
I taught it to Hide.
"This is do, re, mi, fa, so, la, ti, do".
We started like that.
I started dreaming of playing the guitar, recklessly.
He pretended to play the guitar holding a tennis racket.
Back then, I belonged to the tennis club even though I was fat.
I was pretending to play the guitar by holding a tennis racket.
Then suddenly my mother came into my room and I was embarrassed.
As far as I can remember, Hide said that his grandmother bought him a guitar.
When I was in 9th grade, I asked my grandmother crying.
"Grandma, I want to have Gibson Les Paul".
Thus, when I was in junior high school, I sang hit songs medley holding an electric guitar.
He used to sing anime theme songs.
Hide's favorites were "Mazinger Z", "Devilman", and rock version of "Sazae-san".
When the song to perform was decided, he laughed and played.
He found that his guitar sound was different from the sound coming from TV.
Then he asked, "Why is this different?"
I didn't have an effector, so there was no change in the sound.
But I believed that the sound would be different if my guitar skills improved.
I opened the door of his room and saw what he was doing.
Hide ripped the back of the guitar off and was applying glue on it.
I asked him if the guitar was broken.
He replied that the sound didn't change.
I said "It looks to be broken. Is it Okay?",
then he said "Get out of here".
One day, it was noisy so I was wearing headphones.
I threw the headphones out and left the room, then, I heard some noise from my room.
I went back to my room to see if I turned off the recorder, and I found it sounded from the headphones.
At that moment, I thought "This is it!"
"Everyone is doing this way, even Jimmy Page, Ritchie Blackmore and Ace Frehley are doing it this way!"
After that, I played the guitar by raising the volume wearing headphones.
From then on, I didn't even touch the amplifier, and just broke six or more headphones.
Learning guitar became an opportunity to meet rock music.
One day in junior high school, my friend let me listen to KISS's music in his house.
But I didn't like KISS's makeup.
Thus, I borrowed the tape, but I just put it away.
One day, I had nothing to do, so I listened to that tape.
After listening to it, I was shocked, "What's this?"
It was the first time I was hit by a thunderstorm of music.
I started thinking that I was born for rock.
From then on, my Rock'n'Roll life started.
Later, Hide left these words.
“If you do not get away from you of those time, you will not find the answer”
You can't find the answer unless you stay away from yourself in the past.
It took quite a long time for the idea to change.
Time to reach an unimaginable future for an ordinary boy.
He stared at an audience who didn't focus on the concert.
Then he suddenly jumped into the audience and beat him with a guitar.
I was shocked to see it.
He kept replacing members to raise the band's level.
Conflict and anguish arose because of the members to be removed.
I heard he was suffering from members problem.
While strictly managing the members to be professional,
he seemed to be sad every time he changed members.
Sometimes he sobbed in the room.
Then the moment the best members come together came.
They were vocalist "Kyo" and drummer "Tetsu".
How was Hide?
Hide's way of working was...
Hide revealed himself in his work.
That's true.
He came with raw ideas and completed them with the people in the studio.
He was improvised.
He didn't like the typical things.
He bothered us to do this and that.
Actually I didn't understand why he had us do that, but after finishing it, I ended up understanding him.
He was a follower of intuition.
The three major garbage bands in Kanto region that influenced Indies scene.
Saver Tiger was one of them.
Also, X, which greatly influenced Hide's life.
Hide was biting raw meat at a livehouse.
I thought, "Who is that weirdo?"
I didn't want to get very close with him.
But he was very cool.
He was chewing raw meat and was very sensual.
I already knew at that point that he and I would be together.
One of the three major garbage bands in the Kanto region, DEMENTIA.
He had a very fancy makeup, but his personality was quite humble.
But when the performance begins...
Hide's aura was awesome.
I thought, "This guy is crazy".
At that time, Hide said:
Hide said, he hated himself.
That’s why he created the present Hide.
And he said that he was worried about whether he could produce Hide well as he imagined himself or not.
He said that Hideto Matsumoto is desperately producing Hide to be more beautiful than anyone.
He already knew that way at that time.
Hideto Matsumoto produces Hide.
The idea has been reflected in subsequent creative activities.
It's the evidence that there was a character of Hide, back then.
Hide is well-known as an artist with double-sideness.
double-sideness
"Hideto Matsumoto produces Hide".
Does that way of thinking lead to the two sides of Hide?
Flying around in the cranium
Are two worms that resemble me
When they whisper, I can’t refuse.
Are they breeding me? (Breeding)
The relationship between Hide and Hideto Matsumoto was perfectly that of two sides.
He didn’t mix the two together, right?
The two couldn’t be one.
He had as many shadows as light.
He was an expressionist himself, but he might have had frustrations and conflicts about that he could not express.
He was a perfectionist but was not perfect.
Thus, he seemed to have always aimed for perfection.
He was a very delicate person.
So I had to keep distance from him to be friends with him.
Even if you get acquainted with him, you will not understand the whole world of Hide.
He was not a rock star whose personal life was a mess.
He took care of very trifling things.
But when he drank, he used to become violent.
He was spoiled and sincere at the same time.
He was double-faced inside.
There were two worlds within him.
He had a part to enjoy, but sometimes he acted like it was calculated.
“Two-sided” is a word for Hide.
Hideto Matsumoto, the boy, remains intact.
And Hide was born as a new personality.
Hideto Matsumoto had “rock star Hide” inside.
We shared a lot about music.
But I feel like I did not understand Hide in a human way.
The more I think about it, the more I feel it.
Hide’s character was a mask that fascinated people.
But this may had been the cause for the conflict of mind at times.
I knew that there was someone who was controlling me
from the time I was in elementary school.
It’s not simply about the inside and the outside
“Saver Tiger”, the starting point of Hide.
Their leap with ideal members.
However, there was some hindrance on their way.
Hide’s attitude and mindset seemed to be very irrational to me.
Hide was not going to compromise.
I said, “I can’t accept it, I’ll quit”.
Because if I stayed in the band, there would be only conflicts.
Hide had confidence in the composition of the members.
He didn’t want to lose them.
Thus, he made an extreme decision.
January 28, 1987, Disbandment of Saver Tiger
(The red neon sign says “Rokumeikan” which is the traditional and legendary livehouse)
Hide said that if I leave the band, he would also leave the band, and become a hairdresser.
I said “Never say that”.
But I didn’t want to reverse my decision.
When Hide was in Saver Tiger, I asked him to join us but I was rejected.
There was no reason to suddenly stop playing the guitar for a guy who had been enjoying the guitar for so long.
I knew he’d cried a lot.
I received a phone call.
Hide said that he disbanded the band and would quit the music.
But he showed indications of wanting to be together.
I realized that he was still motivated.
At that time, our band was rehearsing.
So I asked, “Will you come to see us?”.
He came and watched the rehearsal. He seemed to have a lot of thoughts.
After that, we went for a drink.
He said “I’m going to join X”.
We were all surprised and very excited to hear that.
SEXX GEORGE from LADIESROOM who was the road manager of X at that time.
I really wanted to stop it.
It was tremendously hard for me to manage Yoshiki.
Then another monster is joining X?
February 1987, joining X
Hide was brilliant.
I knew we will have good chemistry.
I was convinced of it when Hide came in, even before playing with him.
I thought it would be a new beginning.
Hide called me and said that he joined X.
I told him “Good for you”.
I guess the reason why Hide called Tetsu.
Hide knew that Tetsu didn’t want him to quit the music.
That’s probably why Hide called.
Hide said that even if Saver Tiger had disappeared, the members would spread like embers.
He told me, “Tetsu, who put a soul in music is about to form a new band."
"You are going to pursue a splendid rock’n’roll."
And I will take the things that I wanted to show in Saver Tiger to X. And then I’ll change X.”
He said each seed would become four times stronger if dispersed.
It is an intense reminder of my impression.
X has achieved a higher leap since Hide’s joining.
X’s influence has grown in the indie scene more and more.
At that time, Color appeared in the Kansai region.
People used to call it, “X in the east and Color in the west”.
There was an accident during the live performance.
Japan had a custom, so I suggested to have time for self-restraint.
But everyone acted as they pleased.
“Fans want us to keep performing”... claiming like that.
They didn’t listen to me at all.
I asked Hide what to do.
And then he said, “There is the custom in Japan".
"Sometimes you have to follow it.”
He gave me several CDs and said, “How about you do this kind of music?”
Usually people don’t care about other bands like that.
But he said so and I was comforted.
I thought he really cared about me.
X came out of the indie scene and debuted in the major scene.
It changes the history of Japanese rock scene.
In 1992, X was renamed X Japan to advance into the world and moved their base to LA.
The images that came out from the inside.
The photobook which became the new page of expressionist Hide.
“I don’t need a life-size statue of mine."
"I want to create a photo album that reverses the existing image”
April 1992, released the first photoalbum “Mugongeki”
He seems to be possessed by something.
That’s true. He’s possessed. He is running.
Just pressing a button makes him go into the another mode right away.
The man in the straitjacket is staring at something as if he wants to say something.
Is he begging to save him?
Is he wanting to depend on?
Hide’s eyes seemed to say that.
That face still remains in my memory.
In terms of model or subject, he is really the best.
He had the power to go beyond the times.
He is the person who must be mentioned in the fashion field.
Because he transcended the age.
サディストの憂鬱 (The Sadist’s Melancholy)
儀信仏 (Buddhist)
双生 (Twins)
自己中心的な静物 (Self-centered still Life)
浄化 (Purification)
鍵 (Key)
Hide’s poem on each page of the photobook “Mugongeki”.
Was there the will for his solo activity hidden in it?
June 13, 1993, Harajuku
3,000 fans gathered.
Hide decided to do X Japan activities and solo activities at the same time.
The announcement of solo debut.
He was about to perform “OBLAAT” on the street but it was canceled due to the rainstorm.
Please say anything.
I wanted to perform. Let them know this.
I wanted to perform.
I really wanted to perform.
There is a flood in the upper space.
Is there a flood above?
There is a fire in the lower space.
That's it.
Let’s stop here.
He said “I’m scared, I’m scared” in a hoarse voice.
He was very nervous because it was the first tour for Hide.
He was very nervous in order to be perfect.
August 5, 1993, The first single “Eyes Love You” and “50%&50%” were simultaneously released.
January 21, 1994, The third single “Dice” was released.
February 23, 1994, The first album “Hide Your Face” was released.
The pop style of “Eyes Love You” was completely different from Hide’s music until that time.
There was a stereotype like “If Hide released something, it would certainly be this style”.
He wanted to break that stereotype.
“I have a pop tendency as well."
"I put such a tendency intentionally into the single A side."
"I want people, even who don’t know about me to enjoy it”.
[♪Eyes Love You] Red eyes in the city of Sodom, I collect beautiful women. ♪
“It was most difficult to be familiar with my own voice”.
[♪Eyes Love You] : Butterflies and moths fastened to needles ♪
I participated in his singing practice.
He recorded nearly a thousand times.
He was so troubled by recording too many times.
I told him that he didn’t have to record so many times.
It was the only advice I ever gave him.
I’m currently singing as a solo.
However, when I was an amateur who loved rock music, I really hated vocalists.
They all like to meddle in and want to get attentions.
I thought that none of vocalists were normal.
I thought I was far from vocalists.
The way of playing the guitar quietly on one side of the stage was very attractive to me.
That’s why I wanted to be a guitarist.
You can see from the album credit.
It’s written “Voice” instead of “Vocalist” on the album credit.
He seemed to think “I’m not a vocalist yet”.
He was still looking for the directions to go forward.
[♪Eyes Love You] The afterimage of Venus, My eyes love you, let’s love, in a room full of fantasies. ♪
[♪Eyes Love You] Eyes love you, now the eyes have snatched you. My eyes love you♪
The music friends whom Hide met.
Those who should not be lost.
[♪Eyes Love You] I want to indulge you in it.
He would not have planned to invite me to his first tour.
Ran suggested him that Pata should join.
(*Ran(Toshiya Matsukawa) is a guitarist. He was the member for hide FIRST SOLO TOUR '94.)
Then I decided to join.
I didn’t care much about it though.
The first day we met, we drank and went for another round.
We were on our way to another bar.
I didn’t know what the problem was, but Hide was smashing a vending machine.
I stopped him because he was kicking it with his foot.
I asked him if he was upset because it didn't dispense a drink.
He said no, so I asked why he was angry.
He said nothing.
Thus, I said “You idiot. Let’s go!” and dragged him.
And then, I was talking to someone other than Hide at the bar.
Then Hide suddenly stood up to yell, “Am I an idiot?” and hit me.
Later, he called me and said he was sorry.
He said he couldn’t sleep at all and apologized about his behavior.
I said it was okay because it happened while we were drinking and then told him “Let’s drink together again later”.
Then he said “Thank you” and hung up the phone.
After a while, he told me about his solo album and said “I’ll tour later so I want you to join us”.
I was an unknown keyboardist at that time.
I was so excited to meet the member of X.
Hide was waiting for me with his sunglasses on.
I had a heartbeat.
I still remember the heartbeat at that time.
I felt like I was going to see the count of Monte Cristo.
I first met him with such tension and excitement.
Hide’s first impression was...
I felt like I saw the bareface of Kabuki actor.
His skin was very good.
Hide liked Hideyuki.
(* Hideyuki is a guitarist. He was the member of metal band “Schau-Essen”.)
One day, he was seeing Hideyuki on TV.
I was playing behind him then.
He said he’d wanted to be with me since he saw me on TV.
I first met Hide and heard “Yoroshiku”. (*"You are welcome")
Just a handshake with him settled everything.
Normally, they ask me to play (for audition).
But Hide shook hands and said “Yoroshiku”.
The fateful encounter with I.N.A who had been the manipulator of X.
Hide moved I.N.A from the backstage to onstage.
Hide and I.N.A had a lot in common about music.
So all the songs were made by Hide and I.N.A in collaboration.
“The musician Hide is produced by Hideto Matsumoto and INA”.
Hide’s solo activity was spurred through the collaboration.
He said he wanted to make the best team by gathering people he liked.
He invited me to his team.
Instead, he wanted me to exert all my talents only for him.
There were another condition.
He said, if we work together, we have to work on an equal footing.
He said I should not admire him in order to collaborate.
We could collaborate because it was under those conditions.
“I.N.A, use all your talents only for me”.
I.N.A who worked as right arm in Hide’s solo activity.
The life of I.N.A has changed drastically by meeting Hide.
I.N.A, use all your talent only for me.
[♪DICE] Everything in front of me looks like monsters.
The weight of the time and the specter of the past chase me.
I'm being swept away and swallowed by rotting and blowing.
The pipe of consciousness is cut off in a cross shape.
Let the flowers bloom as you think.
Before it is torn up and wilted.
Someday the bud becomes a flower.
I'll tell you who are vomiting the ideal♪
The recording of X was over while we were preparing for a live performance.
Hide decided to stay with X and I came back to our rehearsal room.
There were only people I saw for the first time.
Hide said, “Do something with them until I get back”.
So I tried to practice with them.
But we’ve all just met and shook hands.
We were not friends.
People came into the rehearsal room one by one asking “Is this the studio?”
I.N.A was sitting here, me and D.I.E were sitting there.
Then I.N.A said, “Chirolyn, play 16 bars by slapping” as if he were a teacher.
I thought “What the hell is that guy?”
After that, Hide came back and listened to what we were doing.
He was very angry. “What’s this? You’ve done nothing until now.”
Most members didn’t memorize the songs.
Of course, I was one of them.
When I was told “Next song is... ”, then I wore headphones and copied it in secret.
“Pata, you didn’t practice at all”
He got drunk and released his stress out.
The fight started with “Why is your hair red?”.
We seized each other’s collar and caused a disturbance.
I think that Hide was a person who was clumsy in human relationships.
After fighting, I felt more comfortable with him.
Maybe because I felt in my heart that I wanted to forgive him.
On second thought, I feel as if I was deceived by him.
When we were rehearsing for the first time together, Hide said, “I’m sorry that I like rehearsals”.
He was worried when we were rehearsing.
I asked him “Do we have to do so much rehearsal?”
At that time, Tetsu asked me, “Have you heard Hide’s solo songs?”.
I answered “Not yet”, and he said “The songs are very Hide”.
When I stretch out my hand, it drifts away.
A reward of vanity, wasted and released libido.
The meaning of existence at the end of long suffering.
Me, in the mirror crying to let him know.
Let me water the dried flower of yours, if the flower doesn’t end.
Will the flower bloom or rot?
Dice with only two results.
Let the flower bloom as you think, before it is torn up and wilted.
Someday the bud becomes a flower.
I'll tell you who is spitting yesterday.
Once and for all dice away, dice away
HIDE as a member of X Japan, and hide as a solo singer.
X members decided they would do solo activities, and then the recording company said, “If you do, your albums will sell well”.
Hide was offended by that words.
“Mine sells well? No matter what I do?"
"What does it mean? That’s not music. I don’t want to do those things.”
He had such a conflict.
Unfold the trick in your hand.
Seeds in oil which smell bad enough to be expressed.
If it sprouts, it will be your wonderful dinner.
The remaining food is scattered and rolling here and there.
Take me trash!
At that time, hide became aware of himself who had got caught up in commercialism.
‘What am I doing?’.
“DOUBT” was born in anger of himself.
Hide swore to keep singing “DOUBT” so that he would not forget his mind of that moment.
Hey gentlemen! Is the water there so sweet?
Gentleman, try some musty diamonds.
Doubt, doubt, doubt you.
Flesh are cut and bones are broken.
Tuning of rabies singer.
Doubt, doubt, doubt you.
Flesh are cut and bones are broken.
Don’t you realize that you are surrounded by enemies?
During the live performance, he realized that he was singing and talking to himself in childhood.
I felt it during the live performance.
This guy has been wanting to do something like this.
Even though I am exposed to the shiny wind, I’m gazing at me that can not be melt.
Not even showing the way I walk, the outline becomes clear.
The body dancing in illusion is the pantomime, which is the opposite of my mind.
The reason to fill up wounds with something is only for me to be myself.
Tell me, somebody tell me, please tell me.
Even with voiceless words.
Your voice has not arrived yet.
Even though I look for distorted love, it is answerless and meaningless, I’m just greedy.
My own voice is being swept away.
I can’t hear it until it becomes ashes.
Tell me, somebody tell me, please tell me.
Who is covering my eyes?
My eyes are looking at you.
"I’ve never sang a song about the society."
"I’ve been singing songs only about my personal story."
"The theme of this album is ‘initial impulse’."
"The first listener was myself in childhood."
"So it’s a very private album."
If you do not get away from you of those days, you will not find the answer.
Hide, who has thought that he would not find answers unless he gets away from his childhood.
At the age of 29, however, he wrote to himself in childhood.
To the boy, Hideto Matsumoto
Actually I made an album. The theme is “Initial Impulse”.
I think I made it well.
Probably, this album was created for you.
Do you remember the moment you suddenly changed?
Yeah, I’m talking about the moment when you first met rock music.
I think that you felt in those days and that I feel today is the same.
This album was made to confirm it.
I really wonder.
Why were we so excited?
It’s no exaggeration to say that I have been traveling over a decade to find the answer since I broke up with you.
If I break up with you like this again,
I don’t think I can find the answer.
In hindsight, the answer seems to have existed only at the moment when I was with you.
So I’m going backwards for decades when I was being separated from you.
If you tell me that you have the same feeling I found on this journey,
I think I’ll be able to keep going on this journey that I can’t see the end yet.
- hide
One of the staff said:
"When the live performance was over, I was often called to the rooftop of the hotel by hide."
"On the rooftop, hide used to look at the distant landscape without any special words."
"His breathing back was impressive."
Thank you. Thank you for staff’s efforts.
Thank gods of rock!
Good bye!
alcohol
Once I start drinking, I drink a lot.
No more!
When I first met him, he just drank beer at best.
I blacked out when I’ve drunk the most.
Maybe I drank two bottles of sake.
Finally!
He threw a cigarette lighter into a driving taxi. Boom!
So the taxi stopped making a noise. We shouted “No, no, no, no, no, no!”
He got drunk again in Sapporo.
He was hitting the door of the hotel room making a noise.
That was my room.
I barely avoided the signboard that Hide was wielding.
I didn’t go out of the room because Hide seemed to be completely drunk.
I looked out through the door view and he was rioting.
He suddenly picked up a fire extinguisher and hit the door of my room.
I was really scared.
bang! bang! The door was about to fall off its hinges.
So I blocked the door from the inside.
After a while, he went back to his room.
This is what I heard later, but they said that Hide threw many things at the window.
Later, Pata told me.
If that happens again, I don’t need to hesitate to open the door.
Hide will just look around the room and will go back.
I said “If you are going to go on the rampage here, go back”.
He never acted violently when he was with me.
I saw his rampage a lot.
He used to apologize the next day.
He asked me to forgive him, even though he didn’t recall what had happened.
In hindsight, he was gentle for the degree he was drunk.
He seemed to go on the rampage under the calculation.
Even if he got drunk and rages, he kept being nervous.
brothers
HIDE hid his hard work and his weak side.
Weak side...hmm... How should I say it?
He didn’t reveal his true feelings.
He seemed to have tacitly told me not to get any closer.
A counterpart who doesn’t reveal his true feelings.
And his brother Hiroshi Matsumoto who became a manager of Hide without knowing anything.
At first, I was so nervous that I couldn’t sleep well.
He said “You should tell me everything”.
Sometimes I was hit the back of my head with hard shoe by him.
About six times. While I was driving.
The reason was that I greet in a small voice.
The greeting like “Yoroshiku Onegaishimasu!”.
He said “This industry is stricter than it looks. Do it properly!”
Hide’s attitude toward Hiroshi was sometimes too severe.
Hide didn’t want people would think that he gave Hiroshi preferential treatment because Hiroshi was his brother.
(*in charge of protecting Hide that time)
He wouldn’t have been able to treat Hiroshi, who had no knowledge of the music industry, more than just as an errand boy.
He seemed to draw Hiroshi into the music industry little by little.
I think that Hide, in some ways, felt his younger brother was really close to him.
While he was supposed to live as hide, Hiroshi would be the only place where he could stay as Matsumoto Hideto.
The counterpart whom hide could reveal his bare face.
"I hope that my brother will grow up to be my colleague."
"For the future looked ahead."
For the future looked ahead.
Hide’s activities became more various.
The label established by Hide, LEMONeD.
"I’m not a producer, but a collector."
"If you have something fun, bring it with you."
"I want to make a label like a toy box containing everything."
kowai + kawaii = kowaii
The combination of “kowai(怖い:scary)” and “kawaii(可愛い:cute)”, the new word “kowaii” became its concept.
While designing the stuffs for LEMONeD, he developed clothing business and opened design shops and beauty shops.
He said he was going to seek a new office and told me to go with him.
Hide said, “We can do whatever here because it’s a shopping mall”.
And he asked me “Emi Chan, Would you like to do something here?”
I replied, “Shall we sell juice here? Because the name of the shop is LEMONeD”.
I jokingly said to him, but he told me “Yes, go ahead”.
I told him that I wanted to run a beauty salon and he allowed me to do it.
When I opened the shop, the number of customers didn’t increase.
Hide said, “Be more active”.
So I answered, “Yes, Sir”
The club event hosted by LEMONeD was held.
The days when the internet was not yet available.
They decided to broadcast the event of four places simultaneously via the internet.
The event that surpassed the era.
It may look common nowadays, but it was a revolutionary idea for those days.
The plan originated with Hide.
LEMONeD established by HIDE.
A meeting with a band was the occasion for the establishment of this label.
One of the bands whose life has changed drastically due to the encounter with HIDE, ZEPPET STORE.
They had been releasing their self-produced CDs before the debut in the major scene.
Hide accidentally heard the CDs.
“I realized the mission given to me besides music”.
I felt as if the last piece of the jigsaw puzzle was put in place.
I thought it’s a kind of opportunity or encounter to hear the songs that convey the feeling of composer.
[♪ GOOD BYE] Please songs tell me true, your melody, no matter where I am ♪
The road to major debut.
Hide was different from other companies that only talked about business.
He said that we had a future because our music was awesome.
[♪ GOOD BYE] I'll walk softly♪
Once Hide has fought his staff because of us.
He heard from the staff that Zeppet Store was not commercially viable.
"If you don’t know how to sell, try to like them".
"Listen to their music until you really like theirs".
Hide exploded with fury and hit the wall to make a hole.
He told the staff “You’re fired”.
I was looking at them vacantly.
He looked so disappointed.
He was angry but somehow looked disappointed.
We were happy to see him like that though.
Hide made Zeppet Store debut and decided to tour the US at the same time.
Looking back, he wanted it himself for sure.
Because Hide let us tour with his own money.
May 1996
Ladies and gentlemen, Zeppet Store!
He would have been very proud to see Zeppet Store appealed to American audience.
“Hey, did you see? How are they?” to American audience.
“Japanese are really awesome, aren’t they?”
He seemed to want to appeal those things.
So he kept talking about such things.
He suddenly ran out, climbed into the car and knocked as if he were shouting “Go get'em!”
He ran out shouting and said, “Kimura, I have night blindness so I can’t see ahead well”.
Hide jumped off the car and asked “Have you lost anything?”
Because Seiji got drunk as well, he replied “No” in a drunken voice.
“Yeahhhh!”
When we stopped the car with excitement, the staff’s car crashed into ours. Boom!
Not the staff of Hide’s company but the owner of a sushi restaurant came.
The owner of the sushi restaurant said “Hey! Hide, what are you doing?”
Hide got off the car, saying “I’m sorry”.
We decided to stop the frenzy and go back gently.
On our way back, Zeppet Store’s song came on the radio.
Quote : Video clip they took – 1996
(In the car, Zeppet Store music is coming on the radio)
Nailed it!
Ah! Hide is rushing over.
Hide came. Here is the key.
Hide rushed into us and climbed onto the car we were on.
Quote :  Video clip they took – 1996
The Zeppet Store song is coming on the radio!
YEAHHHH!!!!!
It’s mind-blowing!
This is it!
Good! Let’s go!
I’ll drive.
No, it's dangerous.
Let’s die like this!
No, no!
We have to perform tomorrow morning.
I think Hide was incredibly touched at that moment.
He shed tears of joy and kept cheering us on.
Who else would be such a person?
Hide has produced a number of bands besides Zeppet Store.
He discovered us while creating the music he wanted to do.
“Do you want to release an album?”
It was also Hide who introduced us to Yoshiki.
He was a senpai, an older brother, and parents to us.
(* the name of a band)
There were kouhais who have been discovered by hide but could not meet him.
(*kouhai = older colleague)
(*also the name of a band)
“At that time, they were discovered by Hide while they were active in the name of TRANSTIC NERVE”.
It’s been 15 years since we made our debut.
And I think the reason why we can continue to perform as a band is because of the promise we made at that time.
We have run without hiatus until now because we think hide is watching us.
It’s a sense of mission.
Well, he said our music was awesome.
The word that he told us “awesome” is more precious than any other word.
Even though we couldn’t face him directly, we think this is also a kind of an encounter.
So we are doing as a band believing that he is always watching us.
There are countless musicians influenced by Hide.
June 1996. The production of 2nd album “PSYENCE”
"I felt that the songs I made last year were crappy."
"I deleted the parts that would be better to replace."
The improvisational parts and the theoretical parts.
Speaking of his double-sidedness, he had an impromptu part and a theoretical part.
For example, there was a time when we heard different sounds due to computer data problems.
When he heard that, he said, “What’s this? It’s stunning!”
And he asked me to analyze the reason why it sounds cool.
After this process of analysis, we can have our new techniques available for later use.
Along with this theoretical part, he put emphasis on the attitude of “If it sounds good to me, then I value it as good.”
Ability to absorb various things into himself was really awesome.
September 2, 1996, The release of 2nd album “PSYENCE”
The event to announce “PSYENCE” was very unique that not only musicians but also various performers gathered.
[♪ POSE] The meaning of today that only God knows is overlapped with yesterday.
I’m holding my head that I can’t break.
I know.
I’ll nail it, dear my sun who never sink.
I’m grateful for today and build up stones.
Tell me why.
He was quite nervous when he started his second album activity.
Because he started with a different concept than his first album.
I noticed that he couldn’t hide the nervousness.
He has been a person who kept on amazing and entertaining people since he released his first album.
But he became different when he released his second album.
It was not hide who put band X in the background.
Because he established the style of solo singer Hide, the breadth of his music has expanded.
He was free from the constraints of his hands and feet.
[♪ POSE]: Everythin' POSE. POSE Everythin' POSE.
September 4, 1996, Hide’s solo tour “PSYENCE Go Go” has began.
He was an expressionist.
He was not a mere player, but he was the person who enjoyed creating and expressing himself.
He would have enjoyed the solo activity for sure.
Unexpectedly, he went onstage without the guitar.
I was very surprised.
He had a very objective point of view.
He objectively analyzed the activities of his 1st album and planned the 2nd album activity to be without the guitar.
It is surprising that he has abandoned the guitar even though he was originally a guitarist.
He was not tied to being a guitarist.
At that point, he was already an artist.
He rehearsed again and again and began to think that it would be okay to do without guitar.
It’s certainly true.
He gradually gave up playing the guitar.
He was not simply aiming to discard the guitar.
I think that he wanted to convey the songs and lyrics clearly.
When he finished his 1st album tour and began working on the 2nd album,
I think he’s got the confidence as a vocalist.
For him, that was also a way of expressing himself, rather than he thought “I became a vocalist”.
The fact that he heightened the key of the songs is the proof that he fell into singing.
I’d not thought he was poor at singing until then,
but at that time I thought “He became a vocalist” for the first time.
When he was a member of X, he was allowed to be a strange guitarist in the band.
But when he was soloing, he had to fascinate people himself.
At that time, he found something completely new inside.
He found the answer on the way, rather than he had the answer from the start.
Can I sing tomorrow?
It’ll be okay.
Good morning.
Place staffs at the exit so they can not find the exit.
The skills of the staff also improved responding to Hide’s demands.
However, hide’s performances were not created self-righteously.
He always valued the staff’s opinions.
Okay, do it.
Can I do it? Thank you very much.
He completed his ideas by sharing opinions with members and staffs.
Even if it takes more time, please place the upper cameras as a peeping angle from the top.
Don’t pierce holes.
Do not pierce holes for the side cameras as well.
Just take it from the side please.
Making things with colleagues.
Trust - to obtain purpose
I’m not sure if he knew how to draw people’s talents or he just did it unconsciously.
Anyway his ability to bring out people’s talents was amazing.
He would have been watching everyone on tour.
He would have been quietly watching the staff so they didn’t feel like they were being watched by him.
Hide was able to get people to work for him and follow his decisions, not for the good business prospects.
Simply because he had that kind of charm.
If someone asks if Hide was a man of virtue, you can answer “Yes, Certainly”.
Even though he was not a saint.
He firmly trusted people and entrusted them with work.
He worked with the staff that way, so all the staff presented their idea voluntarily.
He asked the members to come forward.
He told the members that they could stand in front of him on stage.
He used the same vehicles and hotels as the members.
Hide has often told us that the staff are those who does the same things as him.
Usually the staff and singer use different hotels.
But Hide always stayed with the staff.
[♪Hi-Ho] I love your phrase.
The code broken due to my bad feeling is playing a sweet and sad love song.
Like a cartoon with a broken balance, your everyday life is not organized.
Happy days & Happy nights full of things I don’t care.
Hi-Ho! I like your world full of wasteful things.
If you don’t mind, let’s take trivial brats with us.
Getting wet with you, obscene and cool tone...
I felt I had lost the initiative.
Hide made what he wanted to sound clearly and expressed it in live performances.
I was part of his accomplishment, but I felt a little bitter.
[♪Hi-Ho] A song that doesn’t really matter, a trash-like scenario.
I’m dancing to a crappy song.
The victory of your attraction that is not mixed even though it’s idling.
I love your world full of only useless things.
If you don’t mind, let’s dance with useless us.
It was a whole new world of his.
I was astonished.
There was a tremendous evolution between the 1st album and the 2nd album.
I didn’t think it was unexpected.
I knew Hide was into pop.
He wanted to express the feeling of being merged into one.
He seems to have wanted to take out the things from his drawer and play music named Hide.
His second album properly expressed the feeling.
Now, let me take a picture.
Hide’s antenna was extended from Japan to the world.
The second solo album and zilch album “3.2.1” were produced almost at the same time.
Ray McVeigh, formerly a supporting member of Sex Pistols.
Paul Raven, who was a member of Killing Joke.
A band that formed with the two, hide’s challenge to the world, it was zilch.
I was a little bitter.
Because we also wanted to challenge the world stage.
After listening to the CD, however, I was convinced that Hide was being already accepted in the world.
He said he was very nervous at that time.
He said "If this doesn’t work, it’s hopeless."
"I feel like I have a hunch now."
However, the release date that hide wanted was lost due to contract issues.
If zilch’s album was released worldwide just in time, I believe the terrain of the world music has changed.
He advanced crushing a multitude of things to reach that position.
His effort until then was great.
Hide discovered the strength of the Japanese through the activities of zilch.
He was confident that he could produce equal results (as westerners).
“We Japanese also have the strength to compete with the world”.
"I don’t want to conceal the fact that it was produced by Japanese".
I wanted to let them know the beauty and the fun of Japanese when it becomes music.
I believe I won if there is no sense of incongruity despite I set Japanese lyrics to heavy rock on purpose.
Whether I sing in Japanese or English, I want to make sure there is no difference in sound.
In a word, it is something to deliver.
I know that if the listeners are English speakers, I need to make it in English.
But I want to let them know that it was originally made by Japanese.
I want to share the unique complexity and beauty of Japanese with them.
Taking the complexity and beauty of Japanese as a basis for songs.
"I never think that Japanese isn’t suitable for the tone of rock."
"I would like to write Japanese lyrics that have a taste of words that even foreigners can feel magnificence."
Hide’s will is reflected in his third album, “Ja, Zoo”.
Hide and I.N.A embarked on the production of the songs.
Hide, who was speeding up, but after a few month...
September 22, 1997, X Japan disbandment announcement
It was right after the press conference that announced the disbandment of X.
Fans who saw TV gathered.
I was driving slowly through the crowded fans.
I thought hide would open the window and say something to them.
But he was not seen in the rearview mirror.
Looking back, he was lying in the back seat.
"Go faster! How can I show my face to them at this time?"
"Go faster! I’m not able to face them".
He decided not to make fans sad, but he couldn’t keep the promise himself.
He said he was really bitter because he betrayed fans.
At the press conference, fans were gathering in front of the hotel.
We passed the place and went to Hide’s house.
And there we made “Rocket Dive” together.
I remember the day.
Of course we couldn’t finish it.
“INA chan, let’s stop today”.
After that he went out somewhere.
Hide’s regular bar Rally, where he used to drink with his colleagues every night.
After the press conference, he came to the bar alone.
After talking this and that, he finally cried.
At that time, Hide found his direction as he began his solo career,
so I thought he would finish X and commit to soloing.
I couldn’t understand why he was crying.
In hindsight, hide had a deep affection for the band.
For hide, X was the band that couldn’t be better.
The band would have been like a family or home to him.
If someone said “former X member Hide”, he was very angry. “Not former!”
After crying for a long time, hide showed a smiling face talking about the future.
December 31, 1997 X Japan The Last Live
The day after the X Japan The Last Live
January 1, 1998
Hide started his activity as “Hide with Spread Beaver”.
[♪Rocket Dive] It’s generally similar everyday, but it’s OK in its own way.
However, somehow I look up the sky.
January 28, 1998 “Rocket Dive” Release
[♪Rocket Dive] Boys & Girls who totally fell into a reverie.
They laugh after their mind was read.
But it’s not true.
Hide said “Rocket Dive” was a song that was once held off.
At that time, he needed to encourage the fans who had gone through X’s disbandment,
so he decided to work on the song again.
He worked on “Rocket Dive” around the time of disbandment press conference.
So the contents of the lyrics reflect the fans that hide saw.
I felt his strong intention in order to give pleasure to the fans who were wandering.
I think that’s the message of Rocket Dive.
[♪Rocket Dive] You may feel so empty.
There is nothing, which means there is anything.
You can go anywhere, wherever you want to go.
A soaring rocket, launch before it rusts.
Until then, he used to make something inside of himself into messages and then work off into the songs.
But Rocket Dive gave him a chance for change.
[♪Rocket Dive] When you start flying, you are a perfect rocket.
Come on! space age baby rocket dive.
Bungy dive to an invisible place.
Into a universe where new stars twinkling.
Sail away.
I asked him what the “Spread Beaver” means.
He then said “It means this”.
So I said “What? Why did you make such an embarrassing name?”
And he said “I wanted to make the most embarrassing name”.
When someone used the word “workplace”, then he got angry and yelled “It’s not a workplace!”.
Hide had a strong desire to have a band.
He said “You guys are a band. You are not my session musicians”.
He said it was a good idea to give our band a name.
He said there’s nothing to change because we were a band from the start.
We were promoted from our perspective.
Until then we’d been supporting players, but we finally became members of the band.
I really became a member of the band.
[♪Rocket Dive] I want to fly to an invisible place.
High-speeding you are a moment’s spark.
I will continue with rock music in the future.
And it’s like a master’s mindset.
I also belong to Spread Beaver.
[♪Rocket Dive] Into a universe where new stars twinkling.
Sail away
“This year, I will fly like a rocket”. Hide said so.
hide with Spread Beaver and X Japan.
I can’t even compare, basically.
There was a boss called Yoshiki in the band X.
So when I was in X, I freely played the guitar depending on the attraction of Yoshiki.
I was very pleased with the title of a “weird guitarist”.
But now things are totally different.
I have to care everything and have to do a lot of different things.
We used to share all the achievements in X, so one-fifth of the power was assigned to me.
But now, I have to exert my power 100%.
When I get tired, I get tired 100%.
When I lose, I lose 100%.
When I win, I win 100%.
Producing of the 3rd album “Ja, Zoo”.
Pseudo rock star!
He evolved the experience he obtained through the 2nd album “PSYENCE”.
The word created by Hide, “Psyborg Rock”.
The base of the album “Psyborg Rock” existed in the 2nd album “PSYENCE” already.
After disassembling each note played by a human, they reassembled it and stacked it up in several layers.
Then they mixed their computer-generated music with this.
Psyborg rock meant that the tone of human and machine were fused together.
The style created with I.N.A.
Formally I was soloing while I was belonging to X.
I was a solo singer without a band.
Since I didn’t have members, I became dependent on the machine.
When I sing and play the guitar, the computer aids, that was the way I envisioned.
We proceeded in that way and eventually reached here.
We already used that method a lot when we worked on the first album.
We sampled the phrases of the guitar.
Pressing each keyboard key causes a recorded guitar phrase to sound.
We made songs by playing this keyboard.
We’ve been experimenting with such a variety of things.
It’ll not change much.
Rock music will continue to be played through human groups and machine groups.
According to the genre classification in Japan, it’s called “Visual Rock”, but visual rock doesn’t mean music.
So I wanted to declare it a “Psyborg Rock”.
It’s still questionable if this is a music genre.
I’m making noise that it will be fun if this becomes trend.
Hide has an international mindset that is not limited to Japan.
He is working in Japan because he is a Japanese.
But I think he will be successful enough if he release albums here.
I let my colleagues listen to his music, they were all surprised a lot.
Overall, it’s not much different from the previous two albums.
I think I achieved some of the goals I wanted to achieve in this album.
I think this album will strongly show the fusion of my aspiration as a singer and the rock music I wanted to do.
The future spread in front of him
One night, only me and Hide drank without other people for the first time.
Growth of younger brother.
It was the time to achieve recognition as the aide to Hide and to share the plan for the future.
Hide said “Be my spokesperson so you can speak equally to me”.
I was surprised when I heard that.
Hide would have kept it in his mind.
I speculate that he had a harsh whip on Hiroshi because he wanted his brother to be his spokesperson someday.
Zilch had been trying to do overseas activities since then, hide with Spread Beaver had also been on the rise.
“We are going to be very busy because I am aiming for overseas activities”.
He said that he couldn’t fight unless he had the carefully selected staff.
Until then, Hide was the president and the artist.
But from then on he decided to quit the president job and concentrate on the artist job, namely hide’s works.
He didn’t ask me to be the president, but said “Stand in front of people as my spokesperson”.
Artist and manager, older brother and younger brother.
The person he can show his bare face.
“Be my spokesperson”
Hide almost reached the future he always had dreamed of.
May 13th, 1998. release
“Pink Spider” was released following “Rocket Dive”.
The lyrics have storytelling.
The “Pink Spider” means a spider that caresses the delusion.
Web spinned by spiders is “web” in English.
Web is the best way for us to gain information.
The internet is an example.
That’s how the spider that spewed the web to collect information should live only in the web that he created.
The spider who doesn’t know other world is deluding himself that the web he spinned is the source of information.
It is a story of a man who is trapped in a delusion and doesn’t know outside.
At last, the spider longs for clouds and flies to another world called sky.
He admires the clouds and ascends to the sky.
In fact, clouds are only a component of the sky.
After all, the spider ends up becoming just a part of the sky.
I asked him, "Did you borrow the lyrics from a tale?"
"If not, is there a model of the lyrics?"
He didn’t answer.
It seemed that he didn’t want to answer, so I tried to change the topic.
Then, about 5 seconds later, he said “It’s my story”.
My new single “Pink Spider” that is scheduled to be released on May 23th.
[♪Pink Spider] You put a thread of lies on all sides.
You believed your little world was the whole world.
You hurt everyone that comes near you.
You mistake the sky would be square.
“This is all... Everything is like this anyway, isn’t it?”
You said that and that’s a lie.
Because your loud appearance looked lonely, a bird of paradise talked to you strangely.
“Eat butterfly’s wings and come over, to paradise”
“Up there, you may do as you please”.
“I want to go”
“I want wings”.
You ignore the desperate plea of the captured butterfly and are just staring at the sky.
"It is not that I hurt you because I hate you".
"It is just because I have no wings and the sky is too high".
"Use my wings, Spider."
"You don’t know the painfulness of eternal flying as of now."
"But someday, you’ll realize that you’ve been flying only in someone’s hands, and you have called it freedom".
Can’t fly well with the borrowed wings, falling headlong.
“It’s over now”
“Even though I can see the sky”
“It is a failure”
“I wish I had wings...”
Beyond the barely visible sky, birds are heading south “Let’s fly again, cutting these threads off, with my own jet engine, when that cloud passes by...”
Pink Spider, the sky is calling me, Pink Spider
(( In japanese, spider[クモ : kumo] and cloud[雲 : kumo] are homonyms.
It’s interesting that kumo(spider) admires kumo(cloud) and becomes kumo[cloud] ))
Hide came back from LA where he stayed for a long time for promotion.
That night, he finished the recording of a TV show and took part in a wrap-up party as always.
The mood was heightening with his colleagues who have met in a long time.
That night, he talked about the future of “hide with Spread Beaver”.
Anecdotes about TV appearance and performance, schedule of tour, things to do as a band, thought about members...
"I wanna live as a band member."
"I wanna keep going with my band".
I thought someone tried to fool me.
So I decided to come back to Japan.
I couldn’t believe it.
I thought there might be a conspiracy.
I hoped it would be a conspiracy.
< May 2, 1998, Sudden accident by doing cervical vertebra traction treatment during drunkenness >
It was an accident at home.
After driving him home that day, why didn’t I ever think of going up to his place?
The situation would have changed if I did it.
On the day of the funeral, I left the funeral hall holding a portrait of the deceased and people were rushing in.
I told them repeatedly “I’m sorry, I’m sorry”.
I told him “We can’t see anymore. This is the last time”.
I came out of the funeral hall holding a portrait of him, and the voice of people from everywhere sounded like scream.
Compared to their screaming and crying, I thought the portrait was too light.
[♪Flame] Dear my sun, should I know how low & low?
Dear my moon, should I know how low & low?
Dear my stars, if you hear the stars’ lamentation.
Like a wind, it’s a small sound.
Sadness will spread his arms and hug your shoulders.
He will wrap you with the gently shaking dance.
It’s the flame of sadness.
Dear my mind, no matter what misfortunes they are, you need to say hello to them.
Dear my hurts, Let’s get rid of the heavy stuff (like a wind) that you are always carrying.
If it’s going to be forgotten by getting soaked in the night breeze, widen your stride.
Even though there wasn’t hide, the third album was completed.
The person who succeeded Hide was Hide’s right-hand man, I.N.A.
I wanted to complete the album because I saw the people who gathered in Tsukiji.
Excuse me.
Suddenly I recall the memory.
Sorry.
I wanted to deliver hide’s songs to the people somehow.
I will never forget the scene forever.
I was about to complete the album “Ja, Zoo” on my responsibility.
I can’t make music, so I asked I.N.A to complete the album in order to deliver it to people.
I wanted to help people who have cut themselves off from the world and those who have been unable to hear Hide’s music since his death.
The way to completion of “Ja, Zoo”
We had to complete the unfinished album.
Because that’s what hide left.
There were songs in draft while there were the finished.
Among them, only the recorded songs could be completed.
Many people voiced their approval or disapproval on the news that “Ja, Zoo” would be completed without hide.
It was a very hard work both physically and mentally.
Until now, hide has been making a decision.
But from now on, I.N.A is responsible for everything.
The hardest part was to make a decision.
Because the person to decide has disappeared.
The recording began just a week after the funeral.
I was mentally really messed up.
I.N.A, use all your talent only for me
A week before “Ja, Zoo” release, hide’s colleagues started a live tour of 12 locations around the country.
The beginning was Yokosuka, the root and shrine of hide.
But there were a lot of conflicts between fans, staffs and members about the performance.
What would hide want to do?
Wouldn’t he want to play on his tour?
Someone said, “Let’s make it happen”.
“Let’s tour. We have to do it”.
But no one was able to start.
The members and staffs were people who were with hide when he was alive.
When we gathered, I felt as if the air sank to the ground.
Honestly it was extremely painful.
There is no case that you go on tour without hero.
We couldn’t expect what would happen.
We didn’t figure out what to do even though we agonized over it for a long time.
But we concluded that it’s better to do than not.
Hide was gone that way.
But we didn’t think like “It’s over. Dismiss!”
We concluded that it is better to go on tour both for hide and for the fans.
Unlike heretofore, hide can’t guide direction anymore.
Therefore we wondered that who should play hide's role?
I.N.A had to do it.
Who would do it if it were not I.N.A? Who else?
He had been with hide, so we thought it would work well.
It was “Ja, Zoo” tour without hide, so I had to ask a lot of things to I.N.A.
But I.N.A said he couldn’t do everything because he was not hide.
So I worried about what I should do.
We were so nervous until we started. How should we do?
JOE said we were the ones that hide chose, so let’s play as a band.
That was a kind of motive.
[♪Rocket Dive] High-speeding you are a moment’s spark.
Speed freaks baby rocket dive!
Spread your wings and you fly.
Adios to yesterday I just waited.
As soon as the live started, everyone there was crying.
We cried and all the audience cried too.
Everyone cried sadly.
Is there such a concert?
Stress was beyond belief.
The relationship between the members became strange.
The staff also seemed to be out of their mind.
On second thought, it was a little reckless.
But I think it was good to do.
We started in order to finish it but it does not end.
It’s not over yet.
We’re still on that extension.
From the beginning of the last live day for “Ja, Zoo”, I kept apologizing for the audience.
I was grateful to those who came, but I was much more sorry to the audience.
As the tour went on, the audience enjoyed it.
Thanks to that, the members were also healed.
If the tour went on like the first day, members’ hearts would have broken.
In hindsight, we tried not to distinguish between those who were fans from the old times and the general audience who came to the concert.
If we split the two, we had to accept hide’s death.
I was being distressed from start to finish.
But it was meaningful that we laughed, even though the laughter was against our will.
They thought about the future, not the memorial service.
[♪Hurry Go Round] The crazy season is overflowing endlessly.
Completion of “Ja, Zoo” full of agony and conflict.
[♪Hurry Go Round] When the leaves of the ivy widely spread their roots, the scenery seen in the eyes passes away without sound.
What I want to know and listen to as now is “Ja, Zoo” that I made with hide.
I really want to listen to it.
[♪Hurry Go Round] I don’t need to be saddened by the kicking of memory, but that doesn’t mean I’m happy.
I still think that it’s good enough.
At that time, it was enough and it still is.
[♪Hurry Go Round] There is no way to figure out, only the clarity went out yesterday.
We can’t change the fact that hide passed away.
I think finding out how we should live after that is the homework left for us.
I’m not sure if I could continue to be a musician unless I met hide at that time.
I lived a really good time with him.
I really appreciate him for training me this much.
I came up with him doing everything in my power for fear of being left behind him.
Honestly, I still do not believe hide has passed away.
I feel as if he’s here forever, and will say “Let’s do well” again.
He showed a lot of fun things.
He showed wonderful things as well as fun things.
It was love.
He would have been able to act if it was only on stage.
But he was the same offstage.
The people around hide, the members, the staffs and everyone who was connected by hide all had the same mind.
The bond as colleagues became stronger.
If hide was alive and if I had grown even more, we would have dared to jump into the world stage.
Hide was preparing to advance into the world.
I’m going to live life to the full.
I will move on carrying hide’s name on my shoulders, carrying him on my back.
He will continue to play the guitar vigorously.
He will form a band again in the other world.
He will.
Ah, I talked about the other world.
[♪Hurry Go Round] Let’s meet in spring.
Let’s meet again in the spring
17 years have passed since the day.
There are always flowers sent by fans in front of his tombstone.
50,000 fans attended the farewell ceremony.
It was the funeral that was attended by the greatest number of people in Japan's postwar history.
Tokyo, Tsukiji Honganji
Tsukiji temple “Honganji” where the funeral ceremony was held.
One side of the main hall is filled with hearts toward hide.
People’s minds have reached from not only Japan but all over the world.
Thanks to hide, I can be as I am now.
I try to let him hear the voice of fans no matter which venue I go to.
Sometimes I speak aloud “Please let hide listen to your voices”.
I try to spread the greatness of hide to the world.
I think that’s the role given to me.
The 3rd album “Ja, Zoo” is still going on.
On December 10, 2014, “Co Gal” was released in a period of 16 years.
This song was supposed to be on “Ja, Zoo”.
< At that time, the demo tape left by hide was considered
to be impossible to reproduce because only humming remained >
[♪Co Gal] As talking the prepared words in a shy pose, let’s go with the shaking breast fixed.
< Over time, based on vocaloid which is a voice synthesis technology developed by YAMAHA >
Scattering the winds of the dark world with a rapid jet engine.
I.N.A’s challenge has begun
I.N.A collected hide’s voice for four months.
< I picked up every single voice out of the vocal tracks of all hide’s songs and combined it.
It was very difficult and lonely work. >
When I make hide’s music, I feel like I’m with him.
I just want to convey it to people who like hide.
[♪Co Gal] That's not lie. That's not true.
Until the day it collapses, I’ll fuck you and jelly.
Even if everything is disappeared, let’s keep hugging.
Co Gal was completed with a great restoration technology.
“Ja, Zoo” was completed after a long time.
But didn’t he have an empty heart when his work with hide was over?
The important thing is not changing.
The work with hide is the same.
There is no big difference between now and the days when hide was alive.
“I’m still with hide”.
The song was completed as an extension of this thought.
[♪Co Gal] The tragedy in your eyes is like watching a video.
Completion of “Co Gal”
[♪Co Gal] I give a kiss to the part of you where there is no love.
I give a kick to your tomorrow without a dream.
I want to keep delivering hide’s music, beyond generations.
[♪Co Gal] Until the day it collapses
Until two of us burn down
The last count is
Hide’s wings that were called spoiled still keep flapping.
[♪Junk Story] There are so many things I want to see.
The beautiful scenery I have seen before.
I’ve been to Disneyland with him.
Both of us were very noticeable.
Hide said “We are more eye-catching than Mickey Mouse”.
Even though it’s not so meaningful.
Aren’t you going to make the second episode of “Junk Story”?